insead.edu 2018-07-24

# 

                                 INSEAD.EDU
                                       ---
                       Personal Data Protection Charter
                                       ---
Contents
1    Why is this Charter important?
2    Glossary of the main legal terms used in this charter
3 Who is responsible for use of your data in the framework of your
relationship with our departments?
4    Why do we collect your personal data and on what grounds?
5    What personal data do we collect?
6    Who do we share your personal data with?
  6.1     Sharing your personal data with INSEAD affiliates
  6.2     Sharing of your personal data with our partners
  6.3     Other sharing
7    How long do we keep your personal data?
8    Hyperlinks to external sites
9 What are your rights over your personal data and how can you
exercise them?
  9.1     Access right
  9.2     Correction right
  9.3     Deletion right
  9.4     Right to be forgotten
  9.5     Right to restrict processing
  9.6     Objection right
  9.7     Right to digital death
  9.8     Portability right
10     Is your personal data sent abroad?
  10.1    Data transfer within Europe
  10.2    Data transfer outside Europe
11     Data security
12     Do you wish to contact us about this Personal Data Protection
Charter and/or make a complaint to a personal data protection
authority?

   12.1 Do you have a question or suggestion concerning this Personal
   Data Protection Charter?
   12.2 Do you feel that we are not adequately protecting your personal
   data?
   12.3 Submitting a complaint to CNIL, the French data protection
   authority
13      How do you know if this Personal Data Protection Charter has
been amended?
1     WHY IS THIS CHARTER IMPORTANT?
Your privacy is a priority for INSEAD. We are committed to protecting the
personal data of our customers, prospects and online users (hereinafter
“you”), to processing it with the utmost care and ensuring it has the best
level of protection in accordance with Regulation 2016/679 of 27 April 2016
on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of
personal data and on the free movement of such data (“the GDPR”) and the
Law of 6 January 1978 as amended (hereinafter “French law”).
This charter informs you about:
        The personal data we collect about you and the reasons for that
         collection,
        The conditions for use of your personal data,
        Your rights over your personal data and how to exercise them
INSEAD operates this website, accessible to the public at the URL address
https://www.insead.edu (hereinafter “the Site”). The Site is designed to
make available to web-users (i.e. any natural person or legal entity that
visits or uses the Site, hereinafter “the users” or “you”) information
presenting the training programmes and services offered by INSEAD as
well as its news (events, publications, etc.).
The Site also offers functionalities allowing users to contact INSEAD:
contact request, request for brochures, registration for an event or
newsletter, speculative application or response to a job offer, etc. The Site
also offers users the possibility of submitting an application form online for a
training programme offered by INSEAD and makes available to them a
personal space on an online platform (https://apply.insead.edu) allowing
users to complete their application and track its progress and completion.
During your browsing and interaction with the Site or with INSEAD, INSEAD
may need to collect and process personal data about you, in the capacity of
data controller.
                                                                               2

2    GLOSSARY OF THE MAIN LEGAL TERMS USED IN THIS
     CHARTER
Terms           Definitions provided         Explanations of terms in
frequently          by the GDPR                  everyday language
used in this
Charter
Personal data Any information relating     All types of information
(hereinafter  to an identified or          relating to a natural person,
“personal     identifiable        natural  i.e. an individual, directly or
data”)        person (hereinafter a        indirectly identifiable as a
              "data      subject");    an  person distinct from other
              "identifiable       natural  persons.
              person" is considered to
              be a natural person who      For example: a name, a
              can       be     identified, photo, a finger print, an email
              directly or indirectly, by   address,       a      telephone
              reference to an identifier   number, a social security
              such as a name,              number, an IP address, a
              identification     number,   voice       recording,       your
              location data, an online     browsing data on a website,
              identifier or one or more    data linked to an online
              elements specific to         purchase, etc.
              his/her           physical,
              physiological, genetic,
              psychic,         economic,
              cultural      or      social
              identity.
Data          The notion of data           The data protection officer
protection    protection officer is not    (DPO) is responsible within
officer       defined by the GDPR.         the company for compliance
                                           with the GDPR and
                                           applicable national laws as
                                           well as our policies and
                                           practices for managing your
                                           personal data. He/she is also
                                           responsible for liaising with
                                           the supervisory authorities.
                                           The DPO is your first point of
                                           contact for any request
                                           concerning your personal
                                           data.
Processing    Any operation or group       Any use of personal data,
              of operations whether or     regardless of the process
              not they are carried out     used (recording, organising,
              with      the     aid     of conservation,
              automated        processes   modification, reconciliation
              and applied to data or       with other data, transmission,
              personal data sets,          etc. of personal data).
              such as the collection,
              recording, organisation,
              structuring,                 For example, use of your
              conservation,                data for the purposes of
              adaptation or alteration,    order management, delivery,
              retrieval, consultation,     sending newsletters, etc.
              use,      disclosure      by
                                                                             3

                   transmission,
                   dissemination          or
                   otherwise          making
                   available, alignment or
                   combination, blocking,
                   erasure or destruction;
Data               The natural person or      The person, public authority,
controller         legal entity, the public   company or organisation
                   authority, the agency or   which manages your data
                   other body which, alone    and decides how it is used,
                   or in conjunction with     including deciding whether to
                   others, determines the     create or delete a process
                   processing       purposes  and determining why your
                   and methods.               data will be processed and to
                                              whom it will be transmitted.
                                              The data controller is the
                                              main party responsible for
                                              compliant protection of your
                                              data.
Subcontractor      The natural person or      Any natural person or legal
                   legal    entity,    public entity    that   carries  out
                   authority, agency or       processing tasks on the
                   other     body      which  instructions and under the
                   processes        personal  responsibility of the data
                   data on behalf of the      controller.
                   controller;
3    WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR USE OF YOUR DATA IN THE
     FRAMEWORK OF YOUR RELATIONSHIP WITH OUR
     DEPARTMENTS?
The data controller responsible for processing your personal data is
INSEAD, an Association Loi de 1901 (a non-profit association under French
law) and a private higher education institution whose registered office is at
Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau Cedex, France, declared to
the prefecture of Paris, France, under number 59/849 on 28/08/1959, tel:
01.60.72.40.00, email address: legal.department@insead.edu (hereinafter
“INSEAD” or “us”).
INSEAD has appointed a data protection officer in the person of Erika
Gudjonson. She is particularly responsible for independently ensuring
internal application of the rules governing protection and management of
your data and liaison with the supervisory authorities. Here are the contact
details for Erika Gudjonson:
Mrs Erika Gudjonson
INSEAD
Department of Legal Affairs
Boulevard de Constance
77305 Fontainebleau
France
                                                                            4

4      WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND ON WHAT
       GROUNDS?
We collect personal data about you for various reasons.
In general terms, INSEAD collects and uses your personal data to function
effectively and optimise your experience with its departments. Generally,
this processing is necessary for:
     -   the management, processing and tracking of your requests for the
         attention of INSEAD, with some of these operations being
         necessary to perform contractual or pre-contractual measures taken
         at your request (as part of a job application or a training programme
         or following a request to register for an event);
     -   to pursue INSEAD’s legitimate interests in the framework of
         management and supervision of admissions to our training
         programmes, the management and organisation of its prospecting,
         canvassing and communication operations and marketing generally;
You should also be aware that we can only collect and use your personal
data if that use is based on one of the legal grounds determined by the
GDPR (e.g. your consent or performance of a contract concluded with us).
The table below specifically lists the purposes for use of your personal data
by INSEAD, based on one or more of the following legal grounds:
     -   Your consent
     -   Performance of a contract concluded with you
     -   Compliance with a legal obligation
     -   Safeguarding your vital interests
     -   Performance of a public service mission
     -   Legitimate interests of INSEAD in collecting your personal data.
                 Purposes of collecting your personal data
1. Information exchange
Management, processing and monitoring of your requests and exchanges
with INSEAD by means of or initiated via the Site (request for contact,
information or brochures, registration for an event, reservation for a
training session, recommendation of a training programme, job application,
etc.) and INSEAD's relations with its contacts (prospects, students, alumni,
web-users, etc.) generally
                                                                             5

2. Applications and admissions
Management, processing, study and monitoring of applications and
admissions for our training programmes, including provision of a personal
space on the online platform (https://apply.insead.edu) allowing users to
complete their application file and track its progress and completion, or
assess and select applications;
3. Prospecting
Carrying out prospecting, canvassing loyalty-building, communication and
marketing operations in a broad sense, by email, letter or telemarketing
(newsletters, invitations to events, reminders to training programme
applicants, meeting proposals, etc.), including associated technical
operations (e.g. segmentation and targeting in order to personalise
exchanges, enhancement, etc.);
4. Human resources
Management, processing and monitoring of applications and pre-
recruitment procedures, including assessment of professional profiles and
selection of applications, particularly using recruitment assistance methods
and techniques, as well as the creation of an application file (or CV library)
in order to fill certain positions (offers corresponding to your profile which
could also be sent to you for that purpose if you have applied on our Site)
                                                                               6

5. Site management
Management of the Site, including:
    -    access to and benefit of the Site functionalities;
    -    understanding and study of users’ use of the Site and their
         browsing behaviour in order to improve our online
         communications;
    -    improvement of       optimisation    of   Site content   quality   and
         functionalities;
    -    Site administration, particularly for the purposes of security, and for
         identification and diagnostic of problems which may affect
         Site servers;
    -    completion and preparation of studies, analyses, reports and
         statistics, particularly concerning the Site audience or users’
         browsing of the Site;
    -    management and processing of requests from Site users and,
         more generally, INSEAD's contacts, in order to exercise their
         personal data protection rights
6. Laws and regulations
Compliance with legal and regulatory obligations, particularly resulting
from INSEAD's activity.
5     WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT?
Your personal data is particularly collected and processed, entirely or
partially, when you browse the Site and enter information in its data
collection forms (brochure requests, registration for events, applications for
our training programmes, etc.) and, more generally, in the framework of
your relations and exchanges via the Site and subsequent (online or offline)
communication with INSEAD.
Generally, your data is therefore collected directly from you under the
circumstances mentioned below.
In addition to that information, you are informed that the data we collect and
process about you may be enhanced by us via information sources (other
web platforms provided by INSEAD, rental of files, recommendations or
information from third parties, etc.).
Furthermore, more specifically in relation to the information processed in
this respect by our recruitment operations, we use the information you send
us by email to incorporate into our file of applicants (CV library). However,
we may also contact third parties (e.g. recruitment agencies, previous
                                                                                 7

employers, internship supervisors or clients you have worked with in
previous roles) to collect information about you in order to study your
application.
Within the Site, you are informed of the compulsory nature of providing your
personal data on each collection form by the presence of an asterisk
alongside the relevant field(s). Where no asterisk is present, the requested
information is optional.
If the compulsory information is not entered, the request associated with
that collection of personal data (e.g. brochure request, registration for an
event, application for a training programme, etc.) may not be able to be
processed or its processing may be delayed.
In respect of optional information requested, they are generally designed to
provide us with a better knowledge of Site users and their preferences.
INSEAD encourages users to provide this information in order to help
ensure that the contents of our Site remain relevant to your interests and
needs.
6     WHO DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH?
In the course of our activities, we may need to share your personal data.
Obviously, whenever we do so we always ensure optimal protection of your
personal data.
6.1    Sharing your personal data with INSEAD affiliates
We may transmit your personal data to INSEAD affiliates. Since we wish to
be as transparent as possible, below you will find a list of INSEAD affiliates
with whom we share your data and their locations.
 Recipients involved         Location of recipients
    in sharing your
     personal data
Representatives and        France
branches of INSEAD
in France
Representatives and        INSEAD, 1 Ayer Rajah
branches of INSEAD         Avenue,          Singapore
around the world           138676
                           INSEAD,      4th    Street,
                           Muroor Road, P.O. Box
                           No. 48049, Abu Dhabi,
                           United Arab Emirates
                           INSEAD      Middle    East
                           Campus in Abu Dhabi
                           Al Khatem Tower, ADGM
                           Square, Al Maryah Island
                           PO Box 48049, Abu
                                                                             8

                           Dhabi,     United      Arab
                           Emirates
                           INSEAD              NORTH
                           AMERICA,                 c/o
                           Bencivenga       Ward      &
                           Company, CPAs, PC
                           420 Columbus Avenue
                           Suite 304, Valhalla NY
                           10595-1381
                           USA
6.2    Sharing of your personal data with our partners
Any of our service providers and contractual and commercial partners that
may be involved in processing the above-mentioned personal data may
have access to your personal data.
6.3    Other sharing
With public authorities, in response to legal requests, including to respond
to national security requirements or application of the law.
In the context of a transaction, such as a merger, acquisition, consolidation
or sale of assets, we may need to share your personal data with buyers or
sellers.
7     HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
INSEAD has determined precise rules concerning how long we retain your
personal data. This length of time varies depending on the different
purposes and must take into account any legal obligations to retain some of
your data.
The retention time within INSEAD has been defined to allow us to process
your requests (brochures, contacts, registration for an event, job application
or registration for a training programme, etc.), manage and monitor them
and/or      complete     our   prospecting,     canvassing     loyalty-building,
communication and marketing operations, while complying with the principle
of proportionality according to which personal data must not be retained for
longer than necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected.
It is nevertheless specified that all of this data may be retained for longer
than the lengths of time mentioned in this article:
        either with your consent;
        or in the form of archives, to respond to any legal or regulatory
         obligations applicable to INSEAD or for the legal limitation or
         objection periods.
                                                                               9

        or in the form of data reused for the purposes of logs, statistics or
         research.
8    HYPERLINKS TO EXTERNAL SITES
This Site includes links to third-party websites. Those sites are not
managed or updated by INSEAD and are therefore not covered by this
charter. INSEAD does not have any control over the content of those
websites, nor over their confidentiality policies, their use of personal data,
use of cookies, or the way in which they collect, process and store that
data. You are therefore advised to consult the terms and conditions for
collecting and using personal data established by those external sites
before sending them any information.
9    WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS OVER YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND
     HOW CAN YOU EXERCISE THEM?
We wish to inform you as clearly as possible of your rights over your
personal data. We would also like to make it as easy as possible for you to
exercise those rights.
Below you will find a summary of your rights with a description of how to
exercise them.
9.1    Access right
You can ask us to access all of the following information concerning:
        The categories of personal data we collect about you,
        The reasons we use it,
        The categories of persons to whom your personal data has been or
         will be communicated, particularly persons located outside Europe,
        The length of time we retain your personal data in our systems,
        Your right to ask us to correct or delete your personal data or limit
         the use we make of your personal data and your right to object to
         that use,
        Your right to file a complaint with a European data protection
         authority,
        Information concerning their source, when we have not collected
         your personal data directly from you,
        The way in which your personal data is protected when it is
         transferred to non-European countries.
To do this, please simply contact us via email at the address 5555-
itservicedesk@insead.edu, with the subject line “access right: personal
data”, attaching a copy of your identity document showing your signature as
                                                                            10

well as a brief description of the information you want to access. Unless you
indicate otherwise, you will receive the information requested free of charge
in electronic format within one month of receipt of the request, two months
in the case of a request requiring more in-depth research
If you are unable to access your information by email, you can send us your
request by post at the following address:
INSEAD
Boulevard de Constance,
77305 Fontainebleau,
France
In the case of a written request, it must be signed and accompanied by a
copy of your identity document bearing your signature. The request must
specify the address to which the response should be sent. A response will
then be sent to you within one month following receipt of the request, two
months in the event of a request requiring more in-depth research or in the
event that INSEAD receives an excessive number of requests.
9.2    Correction right
You can ask INSEAD to correct and/or update your personal data.
You simply need to send an email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu
stating your full name and with the subject line “correction right: personal
data”, along with a copy of your identity document showing your signature
Also do not forget to indicate the reason for contacting us in the body of
your email, i.e. correction of inaccurate information and the information to
modify, with proof of the correct information where relevant and if you have
it.
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a copy of your
identity document bearing your signature. The request must specify the
address to which the response should be sent. A response will then be sent
to you within one month following receipt of the request, two months in the
event of a request requiring more in-depth research or in the event that
INSEAD receives an excessive number of requests.
9.3    Deletion right
You can also contact us at any time to ask us to delete your personal data
held by us, in one of the following situations:
        Your personal data is no longer necessary in respect of the reasons
         for which it was collected or otherwise processed;
        You have withdrawn the consent you provided as a basis for
         processing your personal data by INSEAD;
        For your own reasons, you consider that one of the forms of
         processing infringes your privacy and causes you excessive harm;
        You no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us;
                                                                           11

        Your personal data is not processed in accordance with the GDPR
         and French law
        Your personal data must be deleted to comply with a legal
         obligation stipulated in European Union law or national law
         applicable to INSEAD;
        Your personal data has been collected as the result of an offer by a
         website aimed at children.
You simply need to send an email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu
stating your full name and with the subject line “deletion right: personal
data”, attaching a copy of your identity document showing your signature.
Also do not forget to indicate the reason for contacting us in the body of
your email (e.g. deletion of your data when you have withdrawn the consent
you provided as a basis for processing your personal data).
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a photocopy of
your identity document bearing your signature. The request must specify
the address to which the response should be sent. A response will then be
sent to you within one month following receipt of the request, two months in
the event of a request requiring more in-depth research or in the event that
INSEAD receives an excessive number of requests.
However, it may be that we are unable to accede to your request to be
forgotten. It should be remembered that this right is not absolute. We need
to weigh it against other important rights and values, such as freedom of
expression, compliance with a legal obligation applicable to us or important
public interest reasons.
9.4     Right to be forgotten
Our Site may contain personal data concerning you. If you no longer wish
for it to be displayed, you can ask us to delete it in one of the following
situations:
        Your personal data is no longer necessary in respect of the reasons
         for which it was collected or otherwise processed;
        You have withdrawn the consent you provided as a basis for
         processing your personal data by INSEAD;
        For your own reasons, you consider that one of the forms of
         processing infringes your privacy and causes you excessive harm;
        You no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us;
        Your personal data is not processed in accordance with the GDPR
         and French law
        Your personal data must be deleted to comply with a legal
         obligation stipulated in European Union law or national law
         applicable to INSEAD.
We are also obliged to take reasonable measures to inform other
companies (data controllers) that process the personal data for which you
have asked for all links and copies to be deleted.
                                                                           12

To have information about you on our website deleted, simply send an
email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu stating your full name and with the
subject line “right to be forgotten: personal data”, attaching a copy of your
identity document showing your signature. Also do not forget to indicate the
reason for contacting us in the body of your email, along with the precise
web address (URL) of the page in question.
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a photocopy of
your identity document bearing your signature. The request must specify
the address to which the response should be sent. A response will then be
sent to you within one month following receipt of the request, two months in
the event of a request requiring more in-depth research or in the event that
INSEAD receives an excessive number of requests.
However, it may be that we are unable to accede to your request to be
forgotten. It should be remembered that this right is not absolute. We need
to weigh it against other important rights and values, such as freedom of
expression, compliance with a legal obligation applicable to us or important
public interest reasons.
9.5    Right to restrict processing
You have the right to ask us to restrict your data, i.e. marking your personal
data held by us (e.g. b y temporarily moving your data to another
processing system or locking your data to make it inaccessible), in order to
restrict its future use.
You can exercise this right when:
         the accuracy of the data in question is disputed;
         Your personal data is not processed in accordance with the GDPR
          and French law;
         the data is no longer necessary to fulfil the initial purposes but
          cannot yet be deleted for legal reasons (e.g. official recording, the
          exercise or defence of your rights in legal proceedings);
         a decision concerning your processing objection is pending.
In the case of a restriction on processing, your personal data shall no longer
be subject to any processing without your prior agreement, with the
exception of its retention (storage).
Your personal data may still be processed for the purpose of official
recording, the exercise or defence of your rights in legal proceedings, or to
protect the rights of another natural person or legal entity, or else on
important grounds of public interest in the European Union or Member
State.
In the case of a restriction on processing of some of your personal data, we
will keep you informed of the date when the measure will be lifted.
You simply need to send an email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu
stating your full name and with the subject line “restriction right: personal
data”, along with a copy of your identity document.
                                                                             13

Also do not forget to indicate the reason for contacting us in the body of
your email.
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a copy of your
identity document. The request must specify the address to which the
response should be sent. A response will then be sent to you within one
month following receipt of the request, two months in the event of a request
requiring more in-depth research or in the event that INSEAD receives an
excessive number of requests.
9.6     Objection right
You have the right to object to us processing your personal data if, for your
own reasons, you consider that one of the forms of processing infringes
your privacy and causes you excessive harm. You cannot prevent us from
processing your data:
        if its processing is required to conclude or perform your contract.
         For example, your data must be processed to validate your
         registration with INSEAD;
        if its processing is required by law or a regulation. That is
         particularly the case when you move to another address;
        if its processing is required to officially record, exercise or defend
         rights in legal proceedings.
You can object to the use of your personal data for the purposes of
marketing communications and particularly advertising. You can also object
to profiling if it is linked to marketing communications (e.g. when we send
you personalised content).
You simply need to send an email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu with
the subject line “objection right: personal data”, attaching a copy of your
identity document showing your signature.
It is important to include the reasons for your objection request.
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a photocopy of
your identity document bearing your signature. The request must specify
the address to which the response should be sent.
INSEAD has two months to respond to your objection request. If your
request is imprecise or does not include all the information enabling us to
fulfil your request, we will contact you to ask for further information within
that time.
However, it may be that we are able to accede to your request. In that case,
we will of course provide you with as clear a response as possible.
Furthermore, any emails and newsletters which may be sent to you will
contain a link you can click on to stop receiving promotional information
from us.
Specifically in relation to your right to object to marketing communications,
we remind you that our marketing partners are responsible for their use of
                                                                             14

your personal data and taking into account your rights, including to no
longer receive offers from them.
9.7    Right to digital death
You have the option to send us instructions relating to the retention,
deletion and communication of your personal data after your death. Those
instructions may also be recorded with a “certified digital trusted third party”.
Those instructions, a sort of “digital will”, may appoint a person responsible
for their execution or, failing, that your heirs will be appointed.
In the absence of any instructions, you heirs may contact us to:
        Access the processing of personal data in order to “organise and
         settle the deceased’s estate”;
        Receive communication of the “digital goods” or “personal data
         containing family memories, transferable to the heirs”;
        Close your personal account on the Site and object to the continued
         processing of your personal data.
In any case, you have the option of informing us, at any time, that you do
not want your personal data to be communicated to a third party after your
death.
9.8    Portability right
This right gives you the possibility of more easily managing your personal
data yourself, specifically:
retrieving your personal data processed by us, for your personal use, and
storing it on a device or in a private cloud for example.
transferring your personal data from us to another company, either by you,
or directly by us, subject to that direct transfer being “technically possible”.
That right covers both your actively and knowingly declared data, such as
your data supplied to create your online account (e.g. email address,
username, age) and the information collected by INSEAD.
Conversely, personal data derived, calculated or inferred from data you
have supplied, e.g. the results of a medical examination, is excluded from
the portability right since it has been created by INSEAD.
You simply need to send an email to 5555-itservicedesk@insead.edu
stating your full name and with the subject line “portability right: personal
data”, attaching a copy of your identity document showing your signature.
Do not forget to indicate in your email the files concerned and the type of
request (data retrieval and/or transfer to a new service provider).
You can also exercise this right by sending us a letter to the following
address: INSEAD, Boulevard de Constance, 77305 Fontainebleau, France.
Your written request must be signed and accompanied by a photocopy of
your identity document bearing your signature. The request must specify
the address to which the response should be sent. A response will then be
sent to you within one month following receipt of the request, two months in
                                                                                15

the event of a request requiring more in-depth research or in the event that
INSEAD receives an excessive number of requests.
You should be aware, however, that INSEAD is entitled to refuse your
portability request. In fact, this right only applies to personal data based on
your consent or performance of a contract concluded with us (for more
details of personal data covered by the portability right: click on the
Purposes and Grounds section). Similarly, this right may not infringe on
third-party rights and freedoms, whose data may be contained in the data
transmitted following a portability request.
10 IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA SENT ABROAD?
10.1 Data transfer within Europe
Personal data benefits from the same level of protection within the
European Economic Area.
We process your personal data on IT servers located in the EEA.
10.2 Data transfer outside Europe
INSEAD transfers, processes and stores your information on IT servers
located in a number of countries outside Europe as set out in the table
below.
You should be aware that protection of privacy and rules allowing
authorities to access your personal data in those countries are not
necessarily equivalent to those in Europe.
In order to ensure standards are adhered to in terms of data and privacy
protection, we impose technical and legal guarantees on all our partners.
11 DATA SECURITY
INSEAD takes all useful and appropriate physical, logical, technical,
functional, administrative and organisational precautions and measures to
guarantee the security of your personal data, with regard to the state of the
art, implementation costs and the nature, extent, context and purposes of
the processing, as well as the risks, whose degree of likelihood and severity
vary, to the rights and freedoms of natural persons, to preserve data
security and confidentiality and guarantee a level of security appropriate to
the risks, and particularly to prevent the data being distorted, damaged or
accessed by unauthorised third parties.
Due to the difficulties inherent in exercising an activity on the internet and
the risks, of which you are aware, resulting from the electronic transmission
of data, INSEAD may not be bound by a performance obligation.
In the event that difficulties occur, INSEAD shall do its utmost to circumvent
the risks and shall take all adequate measures, in accordance with its legal
and regulatory obligations (corrective actions, informing the national
                                                                             16

authority responsible for personal data protection and, where relevant, data
subjects, etc.).
In the event that all or part of the personal data processing is
subcontracted, INSEAD contractually imposes security guarantees on its
subcontractors, particularly in terms of confidentiality in respect of the
personal data to which they may have access (appropriate technical and
organisational measures to protect that data).
12 DO YOU WISH TO CONTACT US ABOUT THIS PERSONAL DATA
     PROTECTION CHARTER AND/OR MAKE A COMPLAINT TO A
     PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION AUTHORITY?
12.1 Do you have a question or suggestion concerning this Personal
      Data Protection Charter?
Please let us know by contacting us here (legal.department@insead.edu) or
by post at:
INSEAD
Boulevard de Constance,
77305 Fontainebleau,
France
We would be delighted to hear from you and it will be a pleasure to respond
as soon as possible.
12.2 Do you feel that we are not adequately protecting your personal
      data?
If you believe that INSEAD does not process your personal data in
accordance with the GDPR and French law, you are entitled to complain to:
       The data protection authority in the European country in which you
        habitually reside, or
       The data protection authority in the European country in which you
        work, or
       The data protection authority in the European country in which the
        GDPR violation was committed.
12.3 Submitting a complaint to CNIL, the French data protection
      authority
You can submit a complaint directly via the CNIL website by clicking here.
Or by writing to the following address:
Commission Nationale de l'Informatique et des Libertés
3 Place de Fontenoy - TSA 80715
75334 PARIS CEDEX 07
                                                                          17

13 HOW DO YOU KNOW IF THIS PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION
     CHARTER HAS BEEN AMENDED?
This Personal Data Protection Charter may be amended at any time,
particularly to take account of any changes to the law or regulations or
changes to our services.
Major changes made will be notified via our Site or by email, as soon as
possible and at least 30 days before they come into force.
When we publish changes to this Charter, we will revise the “last updated
on” date at the top of the confidentiality policy and describe the changes in
the “Version history” page.
We encourage you to regularly consult this Charter to find out how INSEAD
is protecting your personal data.
Last updated on: 22.05.2018
                                                                          18
